

Elena Civati

BIOTECHNOLOGIST

I am proficient in a wide range of scientific subjects and experienced in presenting and explaining scientific matters adapting them to the audience. I'm currently gaining IT skills needed to work in Health Data Science

Skills

Time management and organisation Written and oral communication skills Autonomy Willingness to learn

IT Skills

R programming
Python programming
Unix
Galaxy platform
GitHub
HTML
Ms Office
LaTeX
Educational softwares (Geogebra, Cmap)

Languages

Italian - Native French - B2 English - B1

Areas of interest

Natural cosmetics - Diy cosmetics Scientific communication - Debunking Intercultural meetings Passionate in Maths and Statistics

ADDRESS: 3, Avenue du Jura

01210 Ferney Voltaire (FR)

PHONE: +33-676037025

E-MAIL: elena.civati@gmail.com

NATIONALITY: Italian

DATE OF BIRTH: 08.11.1980

Career Summary

Science Teacher Cias Formazione Professionale (Como, Italy) | Sep 2014 - Dec 2018 Biology, Chemistry, Cosmetology and Dermatology professor, working with both adolescent and adult students

Supporting Teacher Centro Vela Dislessia (Como, Italy) | Nov 2012 - Jun 2018 Helping high school and college students with Specific Learning Disabilities to improve their study method, focusing on Maths, Phisics and Chemistry

Online tutor

eCampus University (Italy) | Feb 2010 - Mar 2013

Guiding students along their university course, helping with choice and observance of their curriculum

Tutor

CESD S.r.l. (Italy) | Feb 2007 - Jul 2016

Teaching scientific subjects to students who couldn't attend school (workers, athletes...)
Tutoring for college students in the Chemistry and Pharmacology area

Morphometry technician

Procter & Gamble | Feb 2006 - Dec 2006

Performing computerized analysis of the spine as part of a prevention campaign against osteoporosis all around Italy

Education

2005

Master's degree in Pharmaceutical Biotechnology, with a final mark of 110/110 University of Milan

1999

Scientific baccalaureate Liceo Galilei of Erba (Italy)

Certifications

"Biostatistics in Public Health" Specialisation on Coursera, JHU (Oct 2021)

"Data Science" Specialisation on Coursera, JHU (Jul 2021)

"Data Science: Foundations using R" Specialisation on Coursera, JHU (Mar 2021)

"Genomic Data Science" Specialisation on Coursera, Johns Hopkins University (Dec 2020)

DELF B2 - GRETA de l'Ain (Dec 2019)

French course B2 2/2 attendance certificate - Ifage Geneva (Nov 2019)

French course B2 1/2 attendance certificate - Ifage Geneva (Oct 2019)

BLSD rianimation and defribillation - Comocuore Onlus (2018)

Pediatric rianimation - Italian Red Cross (2017)

Job security (according to italian law) (2015)

Metacognitive teaching - eCampus University (2011)